export const chapter = "Chapter - 8: Adjectives";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        text: "He is a man. She is a woman. This is a tree. He is a fat man. She is an old woman. This is a tall tree. This is a rat. This is a knife. This is a small rat. This is a sharp knife. The coloured word in the second sentence of each group describes Nouns or Pronouns. These words are called Adjectives. An Adjective is a word which describes Nouns and Pronouns. Example: red, blue, fat, small, etc.",
        questions: [
          {
            question:
              "In the sentence 'He is a man. She is a woman. This is a tree.' What part of speech are the words 'man,' 'woman,' and 'tree'?",
            options: ["Adjectives", "Verbs", "Nouns"],
            answer: "Nouns",
          },
          {
            question: "Which sentence contains an adjective?",
            options: [
              "'He is a man.'",
              "'She is a woman.'",
              "'This is a tall tree.'",
            ],
            answer: "'This is a tall tree.'",
          },
          {
            question: "What is the function of an adjective?",
            options: [
              "To describe verbs",
              "To describe nouns and pronouns",
              "To replace nouns",
            ],
            answer: "To describe nouns and pronouns",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Which word in the sentence 'She is an old woman' is an adjective?",
            options: ["She", "Old", "Woman"],
            answer: "Old",
          },
          {
            question:
              "What kind of words are 'red,' 'blue,' 'fat,' and 'small' in the text?",
            options: ["Adverbs", "Adjectives", "Pronouns"],
            answer: "Adjectives",
          },
          {
            question: "What is the purpose of an adjective in a sentence?",
            options: [
              "To describe actions",
              "To describe locations",
              "To describe qualities of nouns or pronouns",
            ],
            answer: "To describe qualities of nouns or pronouns",
          },
          {
            question: "Which sentence does NOT contain an adjective?",
            options: [
              "'This is a rat.'",
              "'This is a tall tree.'",
              "'This is a sharp knife.'",
            ],
            answer: "'This is a rat.'",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Which word is an adjective in the sentence 'This is a small rat'?",
            options: ["Is", "A", "Small"],
            answer: "Small",
          },
          {
            question: "What word type describes nouns and pronouns?",
            options: ["Verbs", "Adjectives", "Conjunctions"],
            answer: "Adjectives",
          },
          {
            question:
              "In the sentence 'This is a sharp knife,' which word is the adjective?",
            options: ["Knife", "Is", "Sharp"],
            answer: "Sharp",
          },
        ],
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        text: "He is a man. She is a woman. This is a tree. He is a fat man. She is an old woman. This is a tall tree. This is a rat. This is a knife. This is a small rat. This is a sharp knife. The colored word in the second sentence of each group describes Nouns or Pronouns. These words are called Adjectives. An Adjective is a word which describes Nouns and Pronouns. Example: red, blue, fat, small, etc.",
        questions: [
          {
            question:
              "An adjective is a word that describes ______ and ______.",
            options: [
              "Verbs, Adverbs",
              "Nouns, Pronouns",
              "Prepositions, Conjunctions",
            ],
            answer: "Nouns, Pronouns",
          },
          {
            question:
              "The colored word in the ______ sentence of each group describes Nouns or Pronouns. These words are called ______.",
            options: ["first, Pronouns", "second, Adjectives", "last, Verbs"],
            answer: "second, Adjectives",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Adjectives are used to express the qualities or characteristics of ______ or ______.",
            options: [
              "actions, events",
              "nouns, pronouns",
              "conjunctions, adverbs",
            ],
            answer: "nouns, pronouns",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Example words like 'red,' 'blue,' 'fat,' and 'small' are classified as ______ in grammar.",
            options: ["Prepositions", "Adjectives", "Interjections"],
            answer: "Adjectives",
          },
          {
            question:
              "In the sentence 'This is a sharp knife,' the word 'sharp' functions as an ______ describing the knife.",
            options: ["Adverb", "Pronoun", "Adjective"],
            answer: "Adjective",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Adjectives provide additional information about the ______ or ______ in a sentence.",
            options: [
              "verbs, adverbs",
              "nouns, pronouns",
              "conjunctions, interjections",
            ],
            answer: "nouns, pronouns",
          },
          {
            question:
              "The function of an adjective is to modify or describe the ______ or ______.",
            options: ["adjectives, nouns", "verbs, adverbs", "nouns, pronouns"],
            answer: "nouns, pronouns",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Adjectives can specify the ______, ______, or ______ of a noun or pronoun.",
            options: [
              "color, size, shape",
              "action, reaction, emotion",
              "location, time, purpose",
            ],
            answer: "color, size, shape",
          },
          {
            question:
              "The purpose of using adjectives in a sentence is to provide ______ details about the nouns or pronouns.",
            options: ["limited", "descriptive", "ambiguous"],
            answer: "descriptive",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Adjectives are essential for adding ______ and ______ to our language, making it more vivid and descriptive.",
            options: [
              "simplicity, clarity",
              "complexity, confusion",
              "richness, colorfulness",
            ],
            answer: "richness, colorfulness",
          },
        ],
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        text: "He is a man. She is a woman. This is a tree. He is a fat man. She is an old woman. This is a tall tree. This is a rat. This is a knife. This is a small rat. This is a sharp knife. The colored word in the second sentence of each group describes Nouns or Pronouns. These words are called Adjectives. An Adjective is a word which describes Nouns and Pronouns. Example: red, blue, fat, small, etc.",
        questions: [
          {
            question:
              "The colored word in the second sentence of each group describes Verbs or Adjectives.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "True",
          },
          {
            question: "An Adjective describes actions and events.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Adjectives can describe qualities or characteristics of nouns and pronouns.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "True",
          },
          {
            question: "The word 'knife' is an example of an adjective.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question: "Adjectives cannot modify or describe nouns or pronouns.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question: "Adjectives are only used to express emotions.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Adjectives provide additional information about verbs and adverbs.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "An adjective cannot specify the color, size, or shape of a noun or pronoun.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "The primary purpose of using adjectives in a sentence is to provide limited details about the nouns or pronouns.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Adjectives do not contribute to making language more vivid and descriptive.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
        ],
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
